Guide to the Bangs Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1916-46; Series VI; 2.5' (6 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - John Kendrick Bangs, Humorist of the Nineties
      - Notes
        - Humor, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 296)
        - American humor, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 297)
        - Best-selling books of the 1890s, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 298)
        - Working notes (notebook), 1932-33 (Box 47, Folder 299)
        - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 300-01)
      - Manuscripts
        - Draft A (Early draft), n.d. (Box 47, Folder 302-07)
        - Draft B, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 308-34)
        - Draft C, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 335-49)
        - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 350)
        - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 351)
        - Reviews, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 352)
        - Miscellaneous, 1943, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 353)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - "Forty or Fifty Years Ago in Ogunquit", n.d. (Box 50, Folder 354)
    - "John Kendrick Bangs and the Acta Columbiana"
      See: Box 33, folder 257
    - "John Kendrick Bangs: Humorist of the Nineties" (article) (Box 50, Folder 355)
    - ["John Fust"] (ledger of miscellaneous writing), 1945? (Box 50, Folder 356)
    - "Paragraphs Toward a Theory of Poetry"
      - Typescript, 1921 (Box 51 (Oversize), Folder 357)
      - Typescript, bound (with "Taken at the Full") (Box 51 (Oversize), Folder 358)
    - "Taken at the Full: A Symbolic Presentation, By John Fust": typescript, 1926 Apr (Box 52, Folder 359)
      See also: Box 50, folder 356
    - Newspaper articles
      - Wells-Ogunquit Compass (in ledger), 1933-35 (Box 52, Folder 360)
      - "Editorials on World Affairs" ( Old York Transcript and Wells-Ogunquit Compass ): typescripts, 1933-35 (Box 52, Folder 361)
    - Letters to Editors, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 362)
    - Annotated copy of The Complete Works of Geoffrey Chaucer edited by Walter W. Skeat (Oxford: Clarendon Press), 1894 (Box 52, Folder 362a)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 363)
- Correspondence, 1910-63; Series VII; 0.5' (1 box)
  Series VII, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by surname. Significant correspondents of Francis Hyde Bangs or those with more than five letters are listed individually; others are placed in "Letter" general files.
  - "A" general, 1949-63 (Box 53, Folder 364)
  - "B" general, 1950-62 (Box 53, Folder 365)
  - Bangs, Edward M., 1959-62 (Box 53, Folder 366)
  - Barney, Danford, 1919-43 (Box 53, Folder 367)
  - Bartlett, Anna Laura, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 368)
  - "C" general, 1941-63 (Box 53, Folder 369)
  - "D" general, 1936-63 (Box 53, Folder 370)
  - "E" general, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 371)
  - "F" general, 1942-60 (Box 53, Folder 372)
  - "G" general, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 373)
  - "H" general, 1941-61 (Box 53, Folder 374)
  - "J-K" general, 1940 (Box 53, Folder 375)
  - "L" general, 1953-62 (Box 53, Folder 376)
  - "M" general, 1928-63 (Box 53, Folder 377)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (to Lawrence Mason), n.d. (Box 53, Folder 378)
  - Mason, Lawrence, 1910-19 (Box 53, Folder 379)
  - Merz, Charles, 1920-22, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 380)
  - Moché, Joan Hall Bangs, 1961-63 (Box 53, Folder 381)
  - Neal, Lloyd, 1948, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 382)
  - "O-P" general, 1956, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 383)
  - "R" general, 1921 Nov 21 (Box 53, Folder 384)
  - "S" general, 1936-61 (Box 53, Folder 385)
  - St. Paul's School, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 386)
  - "T-W" general, 1936-40, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 387)
  - Yale University, 1941-62 (Box 53, Folder 388)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1951-63, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 389)
  - Sympathy letters (on death of Dorothy Barney Bangs), 1961 (Box 53, Folder 390-92)
- Personal Papers, 1909-61; Series VIII; 2.0' (4 boxes)
  Personal Papers consist primarily of clippings, pamphlets and brochures, and legal papers relating to the life and career of Francis Hyde Bangs, arranged alphabetically by subject, author, or title.
  - Academic records, 1914-25 (Box 54, Folder 393)
  - "American Studies at Yale University for Foreign Students", 1948-49 (Box 54, Folder 394)
  - Art clippings, 1954-55, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 395)
  - Articles, brochures, and catalogs
    - Abbey's Holy Grail (Boston Public Library), 1913 (Box 54, Folder 396)
    - Behrman, J. N. "Conversations with Max." New Yorker, 1960 Feb 6-Mar 19 (Box 54, Folder 397)
    - Goodspeed's catalogs (with John Kendrick Bangs items), 1934-36 (Box 54, Folder 398)
    - Strater, Henry. Exhibition catalogs, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 399)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929, 1943, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 400)
  - Biographical information, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 401)
  - Bust of Francis Hyde Bangs by Anna Glenny Dunbar, bronze, n.d. (Box art, Folder 401a)
  - Diplomas and certificates
    See: Oversize, Box 60, folder 482
  - Education and liberty - Notes (Box 54, Folder 401b)
  - Education and liberty - Clippings, 1934-51, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 401c)
  - The Gunnery School
    - "The Class of 1949 at the Gunnery", n.d. (Box 54, Folder 402)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1949, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 403)
  - Legal and financial papers
    - Divorce papers (F. H. Bangs - Geraldine Hall Bangs), 1932-34, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 404)
    - Estate of John K. Bangs, Jr.: appraisal, 1941 (Box 54, Folder 405-06)
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 407)
  - Magee, John: biographical information, testimonials, 1942, n.d. (Box 54a, Folder 408)
  - Newspaper clippings: miscellaneous subjects, 1920-56 (Box 54a, Folder 409-11)
  - Notes: miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 54a, Folder 412)
  - St. Paul's School
    - Acta Concordiensia, 1911 (Box 55, Folder 413)
    - Horae Scholastica, 1909-11 (Box 55, Folder 414-15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1911-61 (Box 55, Folder 416)
  - Teaching material, 1908-46 (Box 55, Folder 417-24)
  - Toulouse, University of. Qu'est-ce que c'est?, 1919 (Box 55, Folder 425)
  - War records, 1925-42 (Box 55, Folder 426)
  - Yale University
    - Commemorative medal, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 427)
    - Gifts of Francis H. Bangs, 1932-61 (Box 56, Folder 428)
    - Miscellaneous items, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 429)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1928-62, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 430-31)
  - Printed Material
    - The Christian Advocate, including Centennial Number, 1926 September 9; 3 (Box 61)
    - Columbia University Quarterly, 1909, 1936; 3 (Box 61)
      Includes Van Amringe Dinner Supplement with "Poem of John Kendrick Bangs" (1909) and article by Francis Hyde Bangs "John Kendrick Bangs and the Acta Columbiana" (1936).
    - Note to "Mr. Bangs" from Bill Hillman removed from The Carleton Miscellany, Volume 2, Number 3, undated (Box 61)
- Photographs, 1899-1955; Series IX; 2.0' (4 boxes)
  Series IX, Photographs (Boxes 57-59), consists of photographs and sketches of members of the Bangs family, friends and acquaintances of Francis Hyde Bangs, photographs made by Danford Barney, photographs made or collected by James McKeldrin, pictures of the Bangs residence in Ogunquit, Maine, photos of celebrities, and miscellaneous photos. The series is divided into sections for People and Places.
  - PEOPLE
    - Bangs family
      - Bangs, Agnes Hyde, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 432)
        See also: Oversize, Box 60, folder 473
      - Bangs, Dorothy Barney, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 433)
      - Bangs, Francis Hyde
        - Childhood photos, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 434)
        - Scholastic photos (St. Paul's School and Yale), 1911-15 (Box 57, Folder 435)
        - Adult photos, 1919-55, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 436-37)
        - Sculpture photo, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 438)
      - Bangs, Francis N., n.d. (Box 57, Folder 439)
        See also: Oversize, Box 60, folder 474
      - Bangs, Grace Allen Peabody, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 440)
        See also: Oversize, Box 60, folder 475
      - Bangs, Harold Russell, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 441)
      - Bangs, John Kendrick
        See also: Oversize, Box 60, folders 476-477
        - Childhood and youth (Box 57, Folder 442)
        - Adult, ca. 1899-1914 (Box 57, Folder 443-44)
        - Newspaper and magazine photos (Box 57, Folder 445)
        - Caricatures, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 446)
        - Caricatures by Peter Newell, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 447)
        - Related photographs, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 448)
      - Bangs, John Kendrick, Jr. (Box 57, Folder 449)
      - Bangs, Mary Gray
        - Photos, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 450)
        - Framed watercolor portrait, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 451)
      - Bangs, Nathan, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 452)
      - Others, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 453)
        See also: Oversize, Box 50, folders 478-479
    - Friends and Acquaintances
      - Barney, Danford, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 454)
        See also: Oversize, Box 60, folder 480
      - Orr, Janet Mason, 1929-31, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 455)
      - Phelps, William Lyon, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 456)
      - Russell, Lillian, [1905] (Box 58, Folder 457)
      - St. Denis, Ruth, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 458)
      - Others, 1919-29, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 459)
      - Celebrities, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 460)
  - PLACES
    - Danford Barney photographs, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 461)
    - James McKeldrin Archives, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 462)
    - Stuck, Franz: photographs
      See: Oversize, Box 60, folder 481
    - Residences of John Kendrick Bangs (Ogunquit, Maine and Yonkers, N.Y.) (Box 58, Folder 463)
    - Ogunquit, Maine: postcards, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 464)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 465)
  - NEGATIVES
    - People and places (Box 58, Folder 466)
  - FRAMED PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Bangs, John Kendrick: sketch (Box 59, Folder 467)
    - Bangs, Mary Gray, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 468)
    - Bangs, Mary Gray; and unknown child (locket) (Box 59, Folder 469)
    - "Fannie", n.d. (Box 59, Folder 470)
    - Unidentified Bangs family, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 471-72)
- Oversize, 1915-21; 2.0' (1 box)
  - Photos and sketches
    - Bangs, Agnes Hyde, n.d. (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 473)
    - Bangs, Francis N.: etching by B. Landers (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 474)
    - Bangs, Grace Peabody [?], n.d. (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 475)
    - Bangs, John Kendrick (in costume) (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 476)
    - Bangs, John Kendrick (with mother and brothers) (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 477)
    - Unidentified persons, n.d. (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 478-79)
    - Danford Barney photograph: negative, n.d. (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 480)
    - Stuck, Franz. Photo album, n.d. (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 481)
  - Diplomas and certificates, 1915-21 (Box 60 (Oversize), Folder 482)